(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ROBOCOSAN BIRTHDAY LIVE 2023
glory days
空にある何かを見つめてたら
While I was staring at something in the sky
ベテルギウス
作詞・作曲 優里
Betelgeuse
Lyrics & Composition: Yuuri
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
You told me that it was a star
まるでそれは僕らみたいに寄り添ってる
It's just like us, snuggling close together
それを泣いたり笑ったり繋いでゆく
Crying, laughing, we keep connecting them
何十回何百回ぶつかり合って
Clashing dozens, hundreds of times
何十年何百年昔の光が
Light from decades, centuries ago
星自身も忘れた頃に
By the time even the star itself has forgotten
僕らに届いてる
It's reaching us
僕ら見つめ合って 手を取り合って 同じ空
We gaze at each other, holding hands under the same sky
輝くのだって 二人だって 約束した
We promised we'd shine together
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
Endless Betelgeuse, far, far away
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
A magic that connects to someone
僕ら肩並べて 手を取り合って 進んでゆく
Shoulder to shoulder, holding hands, we move forward
辛い時だって 泣かないで 誓っただろう
Even in tough times, we swore we wouldn't cry
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
Endless Betelgeuse, far, far away
君にも見えるだろう 祈りが
You can see it too, can't you? My prayer
記憶をたどるたび 蘇るよ
Every time I trace my memories, it comes back to me
君がいつだって そこにいてくれること
The fact that you are always there for me
まるでそれは星の光と 同じように
Just like the light of a star
今日に泣いたり笑ったり 繋いでゆく
Crying, laughing, we connect to today
何十回何百回 ぶつかり合って
Clashing dozens, hundreds of times
あーあー
Ah, ah...
何十年 何百年 昔の光が
Light from dozens or hundreds of years ago
星自身も忘れた頃に
By the time the star itself has forgotten
僕らを照らしてる
Is shining down on us
僕ら見つけ合って 手繰り合って
We found each other, drawing closer
同じ空 輝くのだって
That we'd shine in the same sky
二人だって 約束した
We promised each other that
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス
From far away, the unending Betelgeuse
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
Is a magic that connects us to someone
どこまで いつまで 生きられるか
How far and for how long we can live
君が不安になるたびに強がるんだ
Every time you feel anxious, I act tough
大丈夫 僕が横にいるよ
It's okay, I'm right here by your side
見えない線を繋ごう
Let's connect those invisible lines
僕ら見つけ合って 手繰り合って
We found each other, drawing closer
同じ空 輝くのだって
That we'd shine in the same sky
二人だって 約束した
We promised each other that
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス
From far away, the unending Betelgeuse
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
Is a magic that connects us to someone
僕ら肩並べて 手を取り合って
Side by side, holding hands
進んでいく 辛い時だって
We move forward, even through painful times
二人だって 笑い合っただろ
The two of us laughed together, didn't we?
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス
From far away, the unending Betelgeuse
君にも見えるだろう 輝きが
You can see it too, can't you? That light
空にある何かを見つめてたら
When I was staring at something in the sky
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
You told me that it was a star
はーい！
Hi!
ハローボ！
Hello-bo!
はい、今日は何の日かって言うと？
Yes, and as for what today is?
そう！
That's right!
僕の７歳の誕生日！
My 7th birthday!
いやあ、僕ももう７歳になっちゃいましたよ。
Wow, I've already turned 7 years old.
というわけで、ホロライブ０期生バーチャルロボットの
So, from Hololive Generation 0, virtual robot...
ロボ子だよー！
...Roboco-san here!
みんな気づいた？そうなんだよ。実は、実は...
Did everyone notice? That's right. Actually, actually...
ほら見て！
Look at this!
なんと、今回から...
Believe it or not, starting from this time...
肌が出せるように進化しました！
...I've evolved to be able to show skin!
どうこれ？
How's this?
すごい新鮮じゃないですか？
Isn't it really fresh?
はい、というわけで、今回はですね、
Alright, so this time,
ハッシュタグ、もちろんあります！
we have a hashtag, of course!
えー、こちらのほうに書いてある...
Um, it's written over here...
あ、こっちだって。間違えちゃった。
Ah, it's this way. I made a mistake.
はい、というわけで、こっちに書いてある
Alright, so, what's written here,
＃ロボ子爆誕2023 が今回の配信のハッシュタグなので、
the hashtag for this stream is #RobokoBakutan2023,
みんなぜひ呟いてトレンド入り目指してください！
so everyone, please tweet it and help it trend!
誕生日トレンド入りたいです！お願いします！
I want my birthday to trend! Please!
というわけでそうなんですよ。ロボ子なんと７歳になりました。
So, that's right. Roboco-san has turned 7 years old.
もう７歳だって。
Can you believe it's been 7 years?
やだー、ラッキーセブンじゃないですか。
Oh my, it's lucky seven, isn't it?
今年はいいことありそうだな。
It feels like good things will happen this year.
高性能が止まらない年になりそうだな。
It looks like it'll be a year of non-stop high performance.
あ、なんか聞こえましたよ。
Ah, I heard something.
そう、実は...
Right, actually...
ステージが今回、ドーン！
The stage this time is... Bam!
かっこいいでしょう！
Isn't it cool!
今回、おしゃれなステージを依頼させていただきました。
I commissioned a stylish stage for this occasion.
え、めちゃめちゃかっこよくない？
Wow, isn't it super cool?
ロボ子っぽくない？これ。
Doesn't it feel like Roboco-san? This.
というわけで、今日はこのステージでたくさんたくさん歌って踊っていきたいと思うので、
So, I'm going to sing and dance a lot on this stage today,
皆さん、まだまだ楽しみにして、ぜひ楽しんでってください！
everyone, please keep looking forward to it and enjoy!
うふふ、今日はなんと、まだお披露目してないあの衣装の全身が、
Hehe, today, believe it or not, the full-body of that outfit I haven't revealed yet...
あったり、しなかったり...
...might or might not be shown...
えーー！
What--!
最後までたくさん楽しみみに待っててくださいね。
Please look forward to it and wait until the end.
それでは、次の曲に行ってみたいと思います。
Now then, I'd like to move on to the next song.
どうぞ！
Here you go!
アザミナ
Azamina
ひらり　ふらり　彷徨ってく　白い夢はもうやめた
Fluttering and swaying, wandering, I've stopped that white dream.
私ずっと知ってたのに　匂いに誘われて落ちてく
Even though I knew all along, I'm drawn in by the scent and falling.
与えられた役目を　訪ねることが怖くて
Afraid to ask about the role I've been given.
流れる日々の答えに　濁したのは心だけ
In the answers of passing days, only my heart was clouded.
定められた箱の中　味気のない寂しさが
Inside the destined box, a dull loneliness...
少し安心してたの　漂う地も知らぬまま
...gave me a little peace, without even knowing where I was drifting.
しまい隠したはずだった　ただの戯言
It was supposed to be tucked away, just idle talk.
分かってる　奥に潜む　その目で見たまぎれもない衝動
I know, hidden deep within, it's an unmistakable impulse seen through those eyes.
ひらり　ゆらり　飛んで行ける　迷い惑い閉じ込めた
Fluttering and swaying, I can fly, locking away my hesitation and confusion.
あなたをもう離さないで　やがて嘘と散っても
Never letting go of you anymore, even if it eventually scatters as a lie.
ひらり　ふらり　彷徨ってく　白い夢はもうやめた
Fluttering and swaying, wandering, I've stopped that white dream.
私ずっと知ってたのに　匂いに誘われて落ちてく
Even though I knew all along, I'm drawn in by the scent and falling.
まとわりつく言葉だけ　何の意味もないくせに
Just clinging words, even though they have no meaning.
背負わされてる重さに　潰れそうでもがいてた
Struggling, feeling crushed by the weight I'm made to carry.
気づかないフリしていたの　壊す術を
I was pretending not to notice the way to break it...
囁いた罠に染まる　覚悟ともう代償恐れただけ
...stained by the whispered trap, I was just afraid of the resolve and the price.
ひらり　ゆらり　舞い降りてく　迷い惑い脱ぎ捨てて
Fluttering and swaying, dancing down, casting off hesitation and confusion.
あなたをもう離さないで　やがて嘘と散っても
Never letting go of you anymore, even if it eventually scatters as a lie.
ひらり　ふらり　落とされてく　白い夢はもうやめた
Fluttering and swaying, being dropped down, I've stopped that white dream.
私きっと戻らない　匂いに誘われて落ちてく
I'll surely never return, drawn in by the scent and falling.
ひらり　ゆらり　飛んで行ける　迷い惑い閉じ込めた
Fluttering and swaying, I can fly, locking away my hesitation and confusion.
あなたをもう離さないで　やがて嘘と散っても
Never letting go of you anymore, even if it eventually scatters as a lie.
ひらり　ふらり　彷徨ってく　白い夢はもうやめた
Fluttering and swaying, wandering, I've stopped that white dream.
私ずっと知ってた　匂いに誘われて落ちてく
I knew all along, drawn in by the scent and falling.
ちゅ、多様性。
Chyu, Tayousei.
我愛你
I love you.
酔いが醒めない
My intoxication won't fade.
我愛你
I love you.
恋が醒めない
My love won't fade.
我愛你
I love you.
様のなれの果て
To the wretched end of this state,
堕ちて
falling.
Get on mine
破滅してみせて
Show me your ruin.
Get on mine
トラウマの味
The taste of trauma.
Get on mine
お手、お座りで　ハイ
Shake, sit, yes.
報酬
Reward.
吐き出してみせなよ
Go ahead and spit it out
Chu!
愛も恋も独占して　僕を独り占めして
Monopolize both love and romance, keep me all to yourself
このまま中毒になるまで　Chu しよう
Let's keep kissing until we become addicted
K-K-K-O-K-O-K-O-Chu
熱く蕩けるくらいに　溢れた気持ちが
My overflowing feelings, hot enough to melt
堪らないでしょ
It's irresistible, right?
K-K-K-O-K-O-K-O-Chu
御愛に　もう一回
For love, one more time
K-K-K-O-Chu
ポンチキ　勝負はいつもトンチキ
Ponchiki, the showdown is always absurd
僕に言わせりゃ　チン・プン・カン　踏んだ最後は　どんびき
If you ask me, it's all gibberish, the ending was a total turn-off
もう何回　遣られればいい？　終わんない
How many more times do I have to take this? It never ends
忘れられない　終わんない
I can't forget it, it won't end
ゲトきめき変愛　夜襲
Get excited, weird love, night raid
喉の奥が　チクン　チクン
The back of my throat is tingling
僕は毒を　含んだ
I've taken in the poison
心臓事　引き摺り出してみせなよ
Go ahead and try to drag out my very heart
気持ちいいね　面倒くさいけど
It feels good, though it's a bother
やっぱ　照れ臭いんだけど
Actually, it's a bit embarrassing
死ぬまで忘れられない　Chu　しなよ
Give me a kiss I'll never forget until I die
イかれた魂は　ゾンビで溢れる
The broken souls are overflowing with zombies
君は僕に恋してる
You're in love with me
ときめく胸に　繋がれろ　降伏しなよ
Be tied to my beating heart, surrender now
行くよ　K-K-K-O-K-O-K-O-Chu
Here we go! K-K-K-O-K-O-K-O-Chu
K-K-K-O-K-O-K-O-Chu
マジで狂えるくらいの　ウツウツとしたが　美しいでしょ
Even the gloominess that's almost driving me crazy is beautiful, isn't it?
K-K-K-O-K-O-K-O-Chu
正解は　終わんない　K-K-K-O-Chu
The right answer never ends, K-K-K-O-Chu
ほらね　御愛に　もう一回
See, for love, one more time
K-K-K-O-Chu
イエーイ！　わーい！　わーい！
Yay! Whoo! Whoo!
天音かなた　お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Amane Kanata here, happy birthday!
ふふ、ありがとう！
Hehe, thank you!
いや、めっちゃ嬉しい。誘ってもらって、めちゃめちゃ嬉しいんですけど。
I'm so happy. I'm really, really glad you invited me.
いや、かなたのこの衣装が出た時から、一緒に歌いたくてウズウズしてた。
I've been itching to sing with you ever since this outfit of yours came out.
いや、もう本当に嬉しくて、もう即、このオファーが来た時に「絶対やります」って言ったんですけど。
I was so happy that as soon as I got the offer, I said, "I'll definitely do it!"
ちょっと今回、二人並んでみて、本当にシナジーありますよね、このルック。
Standing here together, these looks really have great synergy, don't they?
そうだよ。みんな見て見て、これ。赤と青で、これ、どう？
Exactly. Everyone, look at this. Red and blue, what do you think?
双子じゃね？
Don't we look like twins?
え、どうすか？双子だったよね。もう全部もう凄くない？可愛すぎる。
What do you think? We were like twins. Isn't everything just amazing? Too cute.
一部は真反対なんだけど。
Although some parts are the exact opposite.
え、そうそうそうそう。
Oh, right, right, right, right.
一部は...どこ、とは言わないけど...
Some parts... I won't say where...
え？　あ、あ...うん。
Eh? Oh, oh... yeah.
色の話かと思ってた。そうそうそう。
I thought we were talking about colors. Right, right.
え、何の話してるんですか、ロボ子先輩！？
Wait, what are you talking about, Roboco-senpai!?
え？そこは反対じゃないでしょ、全然。そこは大丈夫でしょうよ。
Eh? That part isn't the opposite at all. That part should be fine.
びっくりした、今。これ、反対！？一緒に...
I was surprised just now. That's the opposite!? We're the same...
いや、一緒ですよ。急に嫌だなあ。全然そうだと思わなくても。はいはいはい。
No, they're the same. That's mean all of a sudden. Even if you don't think so at all. Okay, okay, okay.
適当に合わせてみたみたいになっちゃってるじゃないですか。びっくりした。
You're making it sound like I'm just playing along. You startled me.
あ、これ釣れたなと思って。カメラもちょっと見てたしね、今ね、これ。
Ah, I thought I caught you. The camera was watching too, just now.
違うわ！びっくり。気づくわ、さすがに最終的に。
No! Jeez. Of course I'd notice eventually.
や、ね。でも今回この楽曲も、僕実は、ずっと気になってたんで。
Right. But actually, I've been interested in this song for a long time.
え、そう。やっぱさ、この衣装に何が合うのかなと思ったら、最近やっぱ「ちゅ、多様性」キてて、僕の中で。
Yeah. I was wondering what would suit this outfit, and "Chu, Tayousei" has been really big in my mind lately.
いや、分かりますよ。
Oh, I totally get it.
似合うんじゃないの？可愛いんじゃないの？と思って誘っちゃったよね。
I thought it would suit us, and it would be cute, so I invited you.
いや、めっちゃ嬉しいし、やっぱりこの曲って言われた時にロボ子先輩にぴったりだなって思いましたよ。
I'm so glad, and when you mentioned this song, I thought it was perfect for you, Roboco-senpai.
僕もかなたに似合うなって思ったよ。えっへへ。
I thought it would suit you too, Kanata. Ehehe.
いい相性、これ。いい。相思相愛すぎる。やばい。
Great compatibility. Nice. We're too mutual. Amazing.
あ、ありがとうございます。はあ。
Ah, thank you so much. Phew.
じゃあ、これも次もですね、なんかゲストがいるのかな？
Well then, for the next part... I wonder if there's another guest?
なんか凄い清楚な香りがしてくる。
I'm picking up a really refined scent.
あ、なんか後ろからの視線を感じる。清楚な匂いがする。
Ah, I feel a gaze from behind. It smells refined.
ちょっと、僕は次のゲストと交代して参ります。ロボ子先輩！
Well, I'll be switching out with the next guest. Roboco-senpai!
ありがとう！おめでとう！
Thank you! Congratulations!
またね！バイバイ！
See ya! Bye bye!
悲しみは笑いましょう
Let's laugh at sadness
生きるってマリオネット
To live is to be a marionette
セオゾーがスイングしたら
When the theoretical image swings
コーヒーはいかが？
Would you like some coffee?
Un, deux, trois, un, deux, trois, un, deux, trois
私うまく踊ればいいわ
I just need to dance well
痛みも恨みも悲しみも
Pain, resentment, and sadness
混ぜて
Mix them
捏ねて
Knead them
おやすみなさい
Goodnight
Kiss
Shall we dance? 踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望欲望 This is a lie
Despair and desire, this is a lie
Shadow lie 余計なこと
Shadow lie, don't think about
考えないで一つになりましょう
unnecessary things, let's become one
いないいない人間っていない
There's no such thing as a human who isn't here
いない
They aren't here
La la la...
泣きたいのに笑っちゃう
I want to cry, but I end up laughing
強情ってピエロ
A stubborn clown
本当の心隠して
Hiding my true heart
笑うフリをするの
I pretend to laugh
Un, deux, trois, un, deux, trois, un, deux, trois
私うまく生きれないわ
I can't live very well
本音も嘘も不安も
True feelings, lies, and anxiety
溶かして
Melt them
壊して
Break them
おやすみなさい
Goodnight
Shall we dream? 夢見ましょう
Shall we dream? Let's dream
寝ても覚めても This is a lie
Whether asleep or awake, this is a lie
Shadow lie 目を閉じて
Shadow lie, close your eyes
嫌なこと全部全部忘れましょう
Let's forget every unpleasant thing
Shall we dance? 不器用でも
Shall we dance? Even if clumsy
足掻いて向いて This is a lie
Struggling and turning, this is a lie
Shadow step 余計なこと
Shadow step, don't think about
考えないでステップを踏ませて
unnecessary things, let me take a step
Shall we smile? 今だけは
Shall we smile? Just for now
一緒に笑ってみませんか
Won't you try laughing with me?
Shadow dance 今だけは
Shadow dance, just for now
全部忘れて一緒に飛びましょう
Forget everything and let's fly together
Shall we dance? 踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望欲望 This is a lie
Despair and desire, this is a lie
Shadow lie 余計なこと
Shadow lie, don't think about
考えないで一つになりましょう
unnecessary things, let's become one
いいな、いいな
Nice, nice
人間っていいな
Humans are nice
いいな、いいな
Nice, nice
人間っていいな
Humans are nice
La la la...
Shadow... Shadow...
Shadow...
La la la...
ロボ子さん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Roboco-san, happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
や、なんかさっきAZKiの話してました？
Hey, were you talking about AZKi just now?
なんか香ってました？
Was there a scent?
え、なんかちょっと、かなたと後ろから視線とちょっと匂いが
Well, from Kanata, and from behind
there was a gaze and a bit of a smell...
匂いは届いてた？
The smell reached you?
清楚の香りがしたな、と思って
I thought, it smells like purity
本当？本当？
Really? Really?
ということで、皆さんAZKiです！
So, everyone, it's AZKi!
はい、AZKiでーす！
Hi, it's AZKi!
ひさ、やったー！
It's been a while, yay!
本当に久しぶり
It's really been a long time.
ねー
Yeah.
やっと歌えたよ 二人で
We finally got to sing together, the two of us.
そう、一緒に
Yes, together.
なんと、今回ロボコさんが
Actually, this time Roboco-san...
『シャルルダンス』を選曲してくれたんですけれども
chose "Charles" for the setlist.
ロボコさん、選曲理由はどんなところに？
Roboco-san, what was your reason for choosing it?
えー、もうだってさ
Well, it's just that...
あずちゃんとさ、話すたびに
every time I talk to Azu-chan,
うん
Yeah.
僕たちはやっぱりウィスパー曲を一緒に歌いたいよねって
we always say we want to sing a whisper song together.
いや、そう！そう！もうね、ロボコさんとウィスパーな
Yeah, exactly! I've been wanting to sing with Roboco-san...
この感じで歌いたいと思ってて
in this whispery style.
そうそう
Right, right.
だから、今日はこの『シャルルダンス』を一緒に歌えて
So, I'm really happy we could sing "Charles" together today.
めちゃくちゃ嬉しいです、AZKiは
AZKi is so happy!
マジで似合ってた
It really suited us.
あと何か、僕たち二人しかいないのに、なんか多いね
Also, even though there are only two of us, it feels like there are many people.
多い、多いね！
Many, many!
あ、本当だ！多いね！
Ah, you're right! There are many!
あ、みんな気づいてると思うんだけど
Ah, I think everyone has noticed,
みんな気づいてるかと思うんだけど
I think everyone noticed,
今日なんかね、影が付いてるんだよね
but today, we have shadows following us.
なんと、黒子さんですか？
What, are they Kurokos?
黒子さんがいますね
There are Kurokos here.
おやおや
Oh my.
おや、おや。同じ動きが...
Oh, oh. They're doing the same movements...
しちゃう、しちゃう
...the same movements!
しちゃうんですね
They are, aren't they?
増えたってこと？
Does that mean we increased?
AZKiとロボコさんは増えたのか、一人ずつ
Did AZKi and Roboco increase by one each?
分身できちゃう
We can make clones!
しかも、衣装が違うだと！
And they're wearing different outfits?!
え、高性能ってこと？
Eh, does that mean high-performance?
高性能だ！
High-performance!
1回の踊りで2つの衣装が見れるなんてなかなかないからね
It's rare to see two outfits in one dance performance.
ないね、なかなかない
No, it's really rare.
ということで、AZKiはこの黒子と一緒に帰ろうと思います
So, AZKi is going to go home with this Kuroko.
1匹もらおうと思ってたのにー！
I was going to take one too!
もらっていきます！
I'm taking them!
はい、じゃあ仲良く
Okay, get along then.
はい、この後も頑張ってください！
Yes, please do your best for the rest!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとうね、またねー
Thank you! See you later!
またねー！
See you!
悪魔の子
作詞・作曲 ヒグチアイ
Akuma no Ko
Lyrics & Music by Ai Higuchi
鉄の弾が正義の証明
An iron bullet is proof of justice
貫けば英雄に近づいた
If you pierce someone, you've gotten closer to being a hero
その目を閉じて触れてみれば
If you close those eyes and try to touch it
同じ形 同じ体温の悪魔
It's a devil with the same shape and the same body temperature
僕はダメで あいつはいいの？
Is it no good for me but okay for them?
そこに壁があっただけなのに
Even though there was just a wall there
生まれてしまった さだめを嘆くな
Don't lament the fate you were born into
僕らはみんな 自由なんだから
Because we are all free
鳥のように 羽があれば
If I had wings like a bird
どこへだって 行けるけど
I could go anywhere
帰る場所が なければきっと
But if there's no place to return to
どこへも 行けない
I surely won't be able to go anywhere
ただただ 生きるのは嫌だ
I hate just merely living
世界は残酷だ それでも君を愛すよ
The world is cruel, but I still love you
何を犠牲にしても それでも君を守るよ
No matter what I sacrifice, I will still protect you
間違いだとしても 疑ったりしない
Even if it's a mistake, I won't have any doubts
正しさとは 自分のこと 強く信じることだ
What is right is to believe in oneself strongly
鉄の雨が降り頻る情景
The scene of a heavy rain of iron
テレビの中映画に見えたんだ
Looked like a movie on television
戦争なんて愚かな凶暴
War is such a foolish violence
関係ない 知らない国の話
An irrelevant story of an unknown country
それならなんで あいつに組んで
Then why do I hold a grudge against them
黒い気持ち 隠しきれないわけ？
And can't hide these black feelings?
説明だって できやしないんだ
I can't even explain it
僕らはなんで 矛盾ばっかなんだ
Why are we nothing but contradictions?
この言葉も 訳されれば
If these words are also translated
本当の意味は 伝わらない
The true meaning won't get across
信じるのは その目を開いて
What I believe in is the world I touched
触れた世界だけ
after opening those eyes
ただただ 生きるのは嫌だ
I hate just merely living
世界は残酷だ それでも君を愛すよ
The world is cruel, but I still love you
何を犠牲にしても それでも君を守るよ
No matter what I sacrifice, I will still protect you
選んだ人の影 捨てたもの
The shadows of the chosen, the things discarded...
...正義の証明
...is proof of justice.
貫くたび 英雄に近づいた
The more they pierced, the closer I got to being a hero.
気づいたんだ
I realized it.
自分の中 育つのは悪魔の子
What's growing inside me is a child of evil.
正義の裏 犠牲の中
Behind justice, amidst the sacrifices...
心には悪魔の子
...there's a child of evil in my heart.
繁華街 飛ばす上目遣い
In the downtown, I cast an upturned look.
凡くら酔いどれ 自称非凡人
A dim-witted drunkard, self-proclaimed extraordinary person.
使い捨てしたい 屈託と
I want to throw away these worries...
然るべき家から逃げ出したい半場
...halfway through wanting to escape from my proper home.
まぜまぜの おどろの暗い真ん中
In the dark center of a muddled up mess,
はんぱなあんたがよく似合う
a half-baked person like you fits right in.
酔っ払い お祭り事態なんてのが
Being drunk and making a fuss...
お決まりなんだが
...is just the usual, anyway.
人は孤独を殺すため 虚しさを殺すため
People drink alcohol to kill their loneliness,
酒を飲むんだ
and to kill their emptiness.
金も時間も肝臓もな
Money, time, and your liver too.
なんでもやるからさ
I'll do anything.
二人でいいよ
Just the two of us is fine.
あー愛だの恋だの言う其れ以前に俺には一切記憶がねんだよ
Ah, love or romance, I don't remember any of that.
あっちもこっちも限界
Everywhere is reaching its limit.
飲んだら明日に響くというけど飲まなきゃその明日すらもねんだよ
They say if I drink it'll affect tomorrow, but if I don't, there won't even be a tomorrow.
嫌になるぜ もう一杯
I'm sick of it, one more glass.
Don't stop 構わずにもう一杯
Don't stop, regardless, one more glass.
汗ばむような今夜のデモ 全部失くしてなを大繁盛
A sweaty night's demonstration, losing everything and still thriving.
プライド理性捨てりゃいいよ いつわるなら今晩は
Just throw away your pride and reason, if you're going to lie, then good evening.
人差し指一本黙らして 因果省略 没全人
Silencing with just an index finger, omitting cause and effect, a fallen person.
結局いつものことと言えば おしまいなんだけど
After all, saying it's the usual is the end of it.
人は誰もが犠牲者さ 優しい嘘を餌に狩りをするんだ
Everyone is a victim, hunting with gentle lies as bait.
人は誰もが犠牲者さ
Everyone is a victim.
口先火の先苦い酒な
Words, fire, bitter alcohol.
優しくするからさ
I'll be gentle.
一人はヤバ
Being alone is bad.
あー愛だの恋だのイヤイヤと騒いで酔ったら結局誰でもいいんだよ
Ah, love or romance, fussing and saying no, once drunk, anyone is fine.
荒ぶりて傍若無人
Raging and arrogant.
誰でもそれ俺は選ばれたくも 同化せしたけばいいんだよ
Anyone is fine, I don't want to be chosen, I just want to assimilate.
嫌になるぜ もう一杯
I'm sick of it, one more glass.
Can't stop 意味もなくもう一杯
Can't stop, for no reason, one more glass.
馬鹿と煙が梯子酒 登る玉座は空虚な物言わぬ
Fools and smoke bar-hop, the throne they climb is empty and silent.
馬鹿と煙が梯子酒
Fools and smoke bar-hop.
どこもかしこも糞だらけだよ
Everywhere is full of shit.
一番糞なのは
The one that's the most shit is...
お前だ馬鹿
...you, you fool.
あー愛だの恋だの言う其れ以前に俺には一切記憶がねんだよ
Ah, love or romance, I don't remember any of that.
嫌になるぜ もう限界
I'm sick of it, reaching my limit.
んでもないのに何だか生きてるあんたのほうこそ飲まれてるんだよ
You, who are somehow living despite nothing, are the one being swallowed up.
嫌になるぜ もう一杯
I'm sick of it, one more glass.
Won't stop 死ぬ前にもう一杯
Won't stop, one more glass before I die.
ロボ子先輩！
Roboco-senpai!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy Birthday!
わー！ありがとう！
Wah! Thank you!
いや、我々、ついに一緒に歌って踊ってしまったんですね。
Well, we finally ended up singing and dancing together.
やっと一緒に歌えてしまったよ。
We finally managed to sing together.
ねえ、なんかさ、何人かでやることはあっても、二人でやるっていうのは初めてですもんね。
Right, like, we've done things with several people before, but this is the first time with just the two of us.
そうなんだよね。あんまり最近もあんまりできてなかったからね。
That's true. We haven't been able to do it much recently.
踊っちゃった。
We danced.
やっぱりね、すごいやりたかったんだよね、歌。
As I thought, I really wanted to do this song.
え、そうなんですか？
Oh, is that so?
やりたかったよ！
I wanted to do it too!
本当に？
Really?
本当に！
Really!
で、
And...
でも、何にしようかなって、すごい選曲迷って...
But I was really torn about what to choose for the setlist...
めちゃめちゃ変えちゃったんだよね。
I ended up changing it a lot.
え？変えたの？
Eh? You changed it?
めちゃめちゃクロヱに、「え、これどうかな？これやりたい。え、やっぱこれでもいい？」って。
I kept asking Chloe, "Hey, how's this? I want to do this. Wait, maybe this one instead?"
ああ、それかそれか、そういうことか、びっくりした！
Ah, I see, I see. That's what you meant. I was surprised!
そう、めちゃ変えた。
Yeah, I changed it a lot.
はいはいはい。でも、かっこいいやつ出ちゃった。
I see. But some cool stuff came out.
めちゃ合ってましたね、我々。
We were really in sync, weren't we?
合ってた合ってた。ちょっとさっきのあのポーズ、これめちゃ好きなんだけど。
We were. I really love that pose from earlier.
ね、このパカって外すの。
Right? This "snap" of taking it off.
いや似合うなー。めちゃめちゃ似合ってた。
Man, it looks good on you. It suited you perfectly.
でも僕たち弱いんだよね。
But we're weak, aren't we?
謙虚です。
We're humble.
ちゃんとニコニコです、これ。ね。
We're smiling properly here. Right?
しかも衣装も可愛いですよね、やっぱりね。
And the outfit is cute too, as expected.
いや似合ってるよ。これも結構シナジーあるよね。
No, it looks good on you. This also has quite a synergy.
ありますよね。え、これでまた次戻るんですか？
It does. Eh, are you going back with this?
と思うじゃん？
That's what you'd think, right?
もしかして... いや、なんか、ちょっと... え、どうなんだろうね？
Maybe... Well, somehow, a bit... Eh, I wonder how it'll go?
あれれ？おやおやおや？気になる！
Oh? Oh? I'm curious!
じゃあちょっとこのあとも皆さん見守ってください。
So please keep watching after this.
ロボ子先輩がどうなるのか。
What will happen to Roboco-senpai.
ではでは、また遊びましょうね！
Well then, let's play together again!
遊ぼうね！またね！ありがとう！バイバイ！
Let's play! See you! Thank you! Bye-bye!
可愛くてごめん - HoneyWorks
Kawaikute Gomen - HoneyWorks
私が私のこと愛して何が悪いのか
What's wrong with me loving myself?
嫉妬でしょうか？痛いだとか変わってるとか
Is it jealousy? Saying I'm painful or weird,
届きませんね、そのリプライ
Those replies don't reach me.
大好きな御洋服、大好きなお化粧で
With my favorite clothes and favorite makeup,
お決まりのハーフツイン巻いて
With my usual half-twintails tied,
お出かけしよ、日傘持って、こちら手
Let's go out, with a parasol, over here,
幸せだもん！
Because I'm happy!
チュ！可愛くてごめん、生まれてきちゃってごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute. Sorry for being born.
チュ！あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being calculated.
気になっちゃうよね、ごめん
You can't help but notice, sorry.
チュ！可愛くてごめん、努力しちゃってごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute. Sorry for working so hard at it.
チュ！尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious.
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for having high femininity.
ムカついちゃうよね、ざまぁ
You're annoyed, right? Serves you right.
貴方は貴方のことだけど
You do you,
私に干渉しないでください
But please don't interfere with me.
類は友を呼ぶというけど
They say birds of a feather flock together,
届きませんね、その影口
But those backbiting words don't reach me.
重い厚底ブーツ、お気に入りのリュックで
With my heavy platform boots and favorite backpack,
崩せない前髪、クシで解いて
Combing my bangs that won't be messed up,
お出かけしよ、軽い女、ふざけるな
Let's go out. Don't mock me as a "light woman",
重すぎるくらいがいいの
Being too heavy is just right.
重すぎるっつーの！
I said it's too heavy!
チュ！可愛くてごめん、この時代生きてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute. Sorry for living in this era.
チュ！目立ってごめん
Chu! Sorry for standing out.
意識しちゃうよね、ごめん
You're conscious of me, right? Sorry.
チュ！可愛くてごめん、自分磨きしてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute. Sorry for polishing myself.
チュ！ブリっ子でごめん
Chu! Sorry for playing the coquette.
虜にしちゃってごめん
Sorry for making you captivated.
ムカついちゃうでしょ、ざまぁ
You're annoyed, right? Serves you right.
趣味の違い、変わり者と、馬鹿にされても
Even if I'm mocked for my different tastes or being an oddball,
曲げたくない、怖くもない
I don't want to bend. I'm not afraid.
あんたら、どき！
You guys, step aside!
自分の味方、自分でありたい
I want to be my own ally.
一番大切にしてあげたい
I want to treasure myself the most.
理不尽な我慢はさせたくない
I don't want to force myself to endure unreasonable things.
それが私！
That's who I am!
チュ！可愛くてごめん、生まれてきちゃってごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute. Sorry for being born.
チュ！あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being calculated.
人生楽しんでごめん
Sorry for enjoying life.
チュ！可愛くてごめん、努力しちゃってごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute. Sorry for working so hard at it.
チュ！尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious.
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for having high femininity.
ムカついちゃうよね、ざまぁ
You're annoyed, right? Serves you right.
思い出すのは君の歌
What I remember is your song
歌い祝う顔が鮮明で
The face celebrating in song is vivid
どこに行ってしまったの
Where have you gone?
いつも探してるんだよ
I'm always looking for you
思い出すのは君の歌
What I remember is your song
歌い祝う顔が鮮明で
The face celebrating in song is vivid
君に似合うんだよ
It suits you
ずっと見ていたいよ
I want to keep watching you
でも最後に見たいのは
But what I want to see at the end
君の夢の中
Is inside your dream
もう一度また聞かせておくれよ
Please let me hear it once more
聞きたいんだ
I want to hear it
ねぇもっと騒いで怪獣の歌
Hey, make more noise, monster's song
まだ消えない夢の歌唱えて
Chant the song of a dream that won't fade yet
君がいつも歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sing
まだ消えない口ずさんでしまうよ
I end up humming that dream that won't fade yet
思い出すのは君がいた
What I remember is that you were there
ギター持ってる君がいた
You were there holding a guitar
忘れられないんだよ
I can't forget
だから僕ら歌うんだよ
That's why we're singing
でも最後に見たいのは
But what I want to see at the end
君の夢の中
Is inside your dream
もう一度また聞かせておくれよ
Please let me hear it once more
聞きたいんだ
I want to hear it
ねぇもっと騒いで怪獣の歌
Hey, make more noise, monster's song
まだ消えない夢の歌唱えて
Chant the song of a dream that won't fade yet
君がいつも歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sing
まだ消えない口ずさんでしまうよ
I end up humming that dream that won't fade yet
落ちていく過去は鮮明で
The falling past is vivid
見せたい未来は繊細で
The future I want to show is delicate
過ぎていく日々には鈍感な君へ
To you, who are insensitive to the passing days
落ちていく過去は鮮明で
The falling past is vivid
見せたい未来は繊細で
The future I want to show is delicate
過ぎていく日々には鈍感な君へ
To you, who are insensitive to the passing days
ねぇもっと騒いで怪獣の歌
Hey, make more noise, monster's song
まだ消えない夢の歌唱えて
Chant the song of a dream that won't fade yet
君がいつも歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sing
まだ消えない口ずさんでしまうよ
I end up humming that dream that won't fade yet
ねぇ僕ら
Hey, we
手を伸ばして
Reach out our hands
また伸ばして
Reach out again
そんな日々でいたいのに僕ら
Even though we want it to be days like that
懲りずに
Without learning our lesson
手を伸ばして
Reach out our hands
また伸ばして
Reach out again
そんな夜に歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song sung on a night like that
袋に詰められたナッツのような世間では
In a world like nuts packed in a bag
誰もがそれぞれ出会った誰かと寄り添い合ってる
Everyone is cuddling with someone they've met
ざらに紛れ込んだ僕らはピーナッツみたいに
Like peanuts that have slipped into the rough
木の実のふりしながら微笑み浮かべる
Floating a smile while pretending to be tree nuts
幸せのテンプレートの上
On top of the template of happiness
袋に詰め込まれたナッツのような世間では
In this world, like nuts packed into a bag,
誰もがそれぞれふさわしい場所がある
Everyone has their own place where they belong.
テーブルを囲み笑い合うその時さえ
Even when we're laughing around a table,
ありのままではいられないまま
we can't remain as we truly are.
隠し事だらけ 継ぎ接ぎだらけのHome, you know?
A home full of secrets and patches, you know?
噛み砕いても無くならない 本音が歯に挟まったまま
The true feelings stuck in my teeth won't go away, even if I chew them up.
不安だらけ 成り行き任せのLife, you know?
A life full of anxiety, left to chance, you know?
仮初めまみれの日常だけど ここに僕がいて あなたがいる
It's a daily life full of temporary things, but I'm here and you're here.
この真実だけで 胃がもたれてゆく
Just this truth alone gives me indigestion.
化けの皮剥がれた一粒のピーナッツみたいに
Like a single peanut with its disguise peeled off,
世間から一瞬で弾き出されてしまう そんな時こそ
The moment I'm kicked out of society, that's exactly when...
曲がりなりでよかったら そばにいさせて
If you don't mind me being imperfect, let me stay by your side.
共にいられ 揺られ 踏まれ 汚れても 捨てないで 涙になるから
Even if we're shaken, stepped on, or dirtied together, don't throw me away, for I'll turn into tears.
生まれた場所が木の上が地面の中か それだけの違い
Whether you're born in a tree or in the ground, that's the only difference.
許されないほどにドライなこの世界を 等しく雨が湿らせますように
May the rain dampen this world, which is unforgivably dry, equally.
時に冷たくて 騒がしい窓の向こう You know?
Beyond the window, sometimes cold and noisy, you know?
星のひとつも見つからない 雷で見失った気がしてもいい
Not a single star can be found, even if it feels like you've lost sight of them in the lightning.
見せかけだらけ アドレナリン任せのShow, you know?
A show full of pretense, left to adrenaline, you know?
奇跡と加勢の日常だから 腹の中を全部 吐き出してみよう
It's a daily life of miracles and support, so let's spit out everything from inside our bellies.
隠し事だらけ 継ぎ接ぎだらけのHome, you know?
A home full of secrets and patches, you know?
とっておきも出来合いも 残さずに全部食らいながら
While devouring everything, the special and the ready-made, without leaving a crumb.
普通などない 正解などないLife, you know?
A life with no normal and no correct answer, you know?
仮初めまみれの日常だけど ここに僕がいて あなたがいる
It's a daily life full of temporary things, but I'm here and you're here.
この真実だけで 胃がもたれてゆく
Just this truth alone gives me indigestion.
このひとつまみの奇跡を 噛み締めてゆく
I'll savor this pinch of a miracle.
いや、ロボ子誕生日おめでとう！
Wow, Roboko, happy birthday!
おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Happy Birthday!
やった！今日はね、ミックスナッツを歌いたかったから...
Yay! Today, I really wanted to sing Mixed Nuts, so...
おお、嬉しい。
Oh, we're happy to hear that.
ずっと前から僕の父と母のルイとトワに来てもらいました！
I've had my "father" and "mother", Lui and Towa, come here today!
おお、勝手に父にされました、常闇トワです。
I was unilaterally made the father. I'm Tokoyami Towa.
私も勝手に母にされました、鷹嶺ルイです。
I was also unilaterally made the mother. I'm Takanane Lui.
いつもお世話になってます！
Thank you for always taking care of me!
じゃあ我々結婚していたということで、よろしくお願いします。
So that means we were married. Pleased to meet you.
今日限りですけどよろしくお願いします。
Just for today, though. Pleased to meet you.
え、めっちゃ悲しいんだけど。なんでそんなこと言うの？くそぉ！
Eh, that's so sad. Why would you say that? Damn it!
あれ？なんか衣装が、そういえば変わってますよね？
Oh? Your outfit... come to think of it, it's changed, hasn't it?
そうなんです！こちら新しい衣装となっております！
That's right! This is my new outfit!
おおー！可愛い！
Ooh! It's cute!
ちょっとスポーティーな感じで。
It has a bit of a sporty feel.
パーカーはいつもなんだけど...
The hoodie is a regular thing, but...
クールビューティーって感じだよね。
It's like "cool beauty", right?
そうなの、開いてるの、前がパカーンって。
Yeah, it's open, like, "bam" in the front.
え、ちょっとセクシーでいいね。
Oh, it's a bit sexy. I like it.
見せられません！
We can't show that!
おい、見せろよ！
Hey, show us!
映せよ！
Film it!
どけー！
Move!
え、バッグも付いててめちゃくちゃ可愛い。
Oh, it even has a bag. It's so cute.
そうなんですよ。こちらのバッグ可愛いでしょ？
That's right. This bag is cute, isn't it?
お、可愛いい！
Oh, cute!
おへそチラチラ。
Peeking belly button.
そうなんです。え、でも実はこれ、パーカー脱げちゃうんだよね。
That's right. But actually... this hoodie can be taken off.
え、パーカー！？
Eh, the hoodie!?
え、脱げちゃうの？
Eh, it comes off?
脱げちゃう。
It comes off.
脱いだらヤバいんじゃない？
Won't it be bad if you take it off?
え、ちょっと脱いでみてもいい？
Can I try taking it off?
大丈夫かな？YouTubeくんとか大丈夫かな？
Is it okay? Will YouTube-kun be okay?
まだロボ子先輩ロボットだからさ。
But Roboko-senpai is a robot, you know.
あ、じゃあ大丈夫か。
Ah, then I guess it's okay.
じゃちょっと脱いでくるわ！
Then I'll go take it off real quick!
父と母のツーショットで。
While you two, father and mother, take a shot together.
イェーイ！
Yay!
明日離婚します。
We're getting divorced tomorrow.
明日にありこん... 離婚しないでー！
Divorced tomorrow... Don't get divorced!
おおっ！
Ooh!
あ、髪型もさっき、さっきぶり！
Ah, and the hairstyle! It's been... since a while ago!
本当だ！
It's true!
どうですかこれ？
How do you like this?
しかも肌が...
And your skin...
エチエチだよ。
It's so sexy.
よく気づきました！
Good catch!
そう、僕いつも腕、肩の部分は、ロボットの...
Yeah, for me, the arms and shoulders are usually the robot...
…の部分が出てるんだけど…
...that part is showing...
うん。
Yeah.
今回一肌脱いじゃってるんですよ！
I'm showing some skin this time!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いいじゃん！
Nice!
待って背中も可愛くない？
Wait, isn't the back cute too?
え、どう？どうどうどう？
Eh, how is it? How, how, how?
え、いいじゃん！
Eh, looks good!
どうです？フリフリフリフリ…
How is it? Wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle...
こっち！
This way!
ねえちょっと待って、それどうなってるか分かんないからやめてよ。
Hey, wait a second, I don't know what's happening back there, so stop it.
僕でも怖いんだから。
Even I'm scared of it.
どうすんの僕が爆発しちゃったら君たちも…
What'll you do if I explode and you guys also...
でもボタン押しやすそうだね。
But the button looks easy to press.
え、確かに。ちょっと押しやすいんだよね。
Eh, for sure. It's a bit easy to press.
ちょっと衝動があるんだけど我慢してもらっていいですか？
I have an urge, but could you please hold back?
じゃあ、なんかお知らせがあるということなんで、そのボタンを押しましょうかね。ポチ！
Well, since there's an announcement, let's press that button. Click!
だめ！
No!
まあ何ですけど、何もないんですけど。
Well, there's nothing, but...
はい！お知らせは本当にあります！こちら！
Yes! There really is an announcement! Here it is!
どういう流れ？
What kind of flow is this?
ちょっと押されちゃったわ。
I got pushed a bit.
はい！というわけでロボ子のグッズが出ます！
Yes! So, Roboco's goods are coming out!
誕生日記念2023！
Birthday Celebration 2023!
まず一つ目はこちらです！
First one is this!
ドドン！
Ta-da!
アクリルスタンド！
Acrylic stand!
可愛い！
Cute!
今回のこの髪型で、衣装で、WERI先生にスイッチと一緒に描いていただきました！
I had WERI-sensei draw me in this hairstyle and outfit, together with the switch!
めっちゃ可愛くない？めちゃくちゃ可愛い。
Isn't it super cute? It's really cute.
可愛いよね。食べちゃいたいね。
It is cute. I want to eat it up.
食べちゃいたいよね。そうだね。
I want to eat it up. Yeah.
意味深なこと言うな！
Don't say suggestive things!
まだ、まだ分からないからみんなには。
Not yet, you guys don't know yet.
じゃあ次のやつ行ってみましょう。次こちら！
Then let's look at the next one. Next is this!
ランダム缶バッジ！
Random tin badges!
こちらは街子マキ先生に描いていただきました！
These were drawn by Machiko-maki-sensei!
おー、色んな衣装と髪型のロボ子だ。
Oh, it's Roboco in various outfits and hairstyles.
新しいやつのこれも。
This one in the new outfit too.
可愛いですよ、色んな種類があって。
They're cute, there are many types.
全部集めたい。
I want to collect them all.
どれにしようかな。
Which one should I get?
ランダムだから選べません。
Since they're random, you can't choose.
全部ゲットしてみてください！
Please try to get them all!
はい！そして次はこちら！
Yes! And next is this!
スマホリング！
Smartphone ring!
おお、おしゃれ。
Oh, stylish.
そう、今回ステージにも歯車のやつをモチーフいっぱい付けさせていただいたんですけど。
Yes, this time I had many gear motifs on the stage too.
スマホリングも今回ロゴ入りで歯車のやつにさせていただきました。
The smartphone ring also has the logo and gear design.
チャームもね、取ったり外したりもできるの。取ったり外したり…
The charm can be removed and attached. Removed and attached...
付け替えができるのでぜひぜひ。
It's interchangeable, so please do.
そして次はこちら！
And next is this!
ジャジャン！なんと！
Ta-da! What's more!
僕と同じバッグがゲットできます！
You can get the same bag as me!
いいじゃんこれ。
This is great.
結構ね、ポリキャンバス系のしっかりした素材で作られているので、普段使いめっちゃしやすいと思います。
It's made of a sturdy poly-canvas material, so I think it's very easy to use for daily life.
舞踏しながらこれ付けるっていうのも。
While moving, wearing this too.
ぜひ、どうですか？
So, how about it?
欲しい、欲しい！
I want it, I want it!
一緒にお揃いだろうね。
It'll be matching.
欲しい。父と母にはくれますか？
I want it. Will you give one to father and mother?
あげます！
I'll give it!
やったー！
Yay!
買ってください。
Please buy it.
やばい、父母バレしちゃうなこれ。
Oh no, father and mother will be revealed.
じゃあ家族とロボコの家族とお揃いボディバッグだね。
A matching body bag with the family and Roboco's family.
これがないと父と母になってくれなかったってこと？
If it weren't for this, they wouldn't have become father and mother?
ちょっと待って。
Wait a minute.
明日には離婚だけど。
I'm getting a divorce tomorrow, though.
ねー！
Hey!
しー！
Shh!
そんな残酷なこと突きつけちゃだめ。
Don't say such cruel things.
ごめんごめんごめん。
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
はい、最後はこちら！
Yes, lastly this!
記念ボイス！
Commemorative voice!
「僕と過ごす甘いひととき」ボイス販売もあります。
"A sweet moment spent with me" voice packs are also on sale.
あら甘いひとときね。
Oh, a sweet moment.
僕ちょっと大人になっちゃった？
Did I become a bit more adult?
あ、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
じゃあもう一人立ちできるということで…
Then you can stand on your own now...
違う、違う、違う、違うから！
No, no, no, it's not like that!
なんかまずい方向になってるから早く、早く！
It's going in a bad direction, so hurry, hurry!
はいというわけでこちらですね。
Yes, so here it is.
フルセット購入にはもちろん数量限定で、僕の直筆サインと複製メッセージ入りのポストカードがついてきます！
For the full set purchase, of course in limited quantities, it comes with a postcard with my handwritten signature and a duplicated message!
もちろん通常版にもサインとメッセージ入りのポストカードがありますので、ぜひフルセットで購入してみてください！
Of course, the regular version also has a postcard with a signature and message, so please try to buy the full set!
数量限定だから急げよ！
It's limited quantity, so hurry up!
はい、というわけで。
Yes, so...
ということで大人になったね、ロボ子。
So you've become an adult, Roboco.
アハン。
*Sigh*.
旅立ちの日。
Departure day.
そうだね、旅立ちの日。
That's right, departure day.
もう父とママとパパいらないね。
You don't need father and mama and papa anymore.
いる、いるけど、いるけど。
I do, I do, but...
じゃあこの辺で。
Well, let's end it here.
ねえ泣かないでよ、ごめん。
Hey, don't cry, sorry.
帰ろうか。
Shall we go home?
ギブ父と母。
Give up father and mother.
やばいケツが…
Oh no, the butt...
ケツが…
The butt...
待って…
Wait...
僕これさ…
Is this...
バイバーイ！
Bye bye!
レンタルパパ？レンタルパパ？
Rental papa? Rental papa?
あ、今日もお疲れ様ですね。
Ah, thanks for the hard work today.
あ、今日レンタル疲れたな。
Ah, I'm tired of rental today.
待って、僕ってこれレンタル父と母だったってこと？
Wait, does that mean these were rental father and mother?
心が虚しいんだけど。
My heart feels empty.
でもありがと、またね！
But thanks, see you later!
ねえねえ言いたいことがたくさんあるけどオーバーヒート
Hey, hey, there's so much I want to say, but I'm overheating
グルグル回る頭の中
Inside my spinning head
転んでも笑って
Keep laughing even if you fall
そばにいてね
Please stay by my side
全然足りないステイブル
My stability is not enough at all
でも気合バンザイ
But my spirit is high
やる気もマンタン
I'm full of motivation
伝わるといいな
I hope it reaches you
君に for you
For you
ポンでもキラキラに
Even if I'm "pon," I want to shine
輝きたい
Brightly
glory days
なんだかなぁ つまずいちゃうの
For some reason, I keep tripping up
パーフェクトにこなしたいのに
Even though I want to do things perfectly
こんがらがる配線
My wiring gets all tangled
もつれる手足
My hands and feet get twisted
始終こんなんじゃマジ疎い
If it's always like this, I'm really clueless
たまには高性能って言われたい
Sometimes I want to be called high-spec
意地悪だってしちゃいたいね
I want to be a bit mischievous too
いいでしょ？
That's okay, right?
モロバレなブラフ
An obvious bluff
でもわからないふりして
But pretend you don't notice
僕に騙されてよ
And let me fool you
ねえねえ 言いたいことが
Hey, there's so much
たくさんあるけど
I want to say
オーバーヒート
Overheating
ぐるぐる回る 頭の中
My head is spinning around and around
転んでも笑って
Keep laughing even if you fall
そばにいてね
Please stay by my side
全然足りないステイブル
My stability is not enough at all
でも気合バンザイ
But my spirit is high
やる気もマンタン
I'm full of motivation
伝わるといいな
I hope it reaches you
君に for you
For you
ポンでもキラキラに
Even if I'm "pon," I want to shine
輝きたい
Brightly
glory days
現実もゲームのように
I wish reality could be like a game
パチっと決めていけたらいいのにな
Where everything clicks perfectly into place
少々噛みつきメンタル
A slightly biting mentality
キャパ子紹介書いたらむせちゃった
I choked while writing the Capa-ko introduction
OH AH
時に収まるペンデュラム
Sometimes the pendulum settles
指し示す行くべき道を
Pointing to the path I should take
難しすぎてわからないままで
It's too difficult, so while I still don't understand
またポンしちゃうよ
I'll end up being "pon" again
ねえねえ 言いたいことが
Hey, there's so much
たくさんあるけど
I want to say
オーバーヒート
Overheating
ぐるぐる回る 頭の中
My head is spinning around and around
転んでも笑って
Keep laughing even if you fall
そばにいてね
Please stay by my side
全然足りないステイブル
My stability is not enough at all
でも気合バンザイ
But my spirit is high
やる気もマンタン
I'm full of motivation
伝わるといいな
I hope it reaches you
君に for you
For you
ポンでもキラキラに
Even if I'm "pon," I want to shine
輝きたい
Brightly
glory days
ろぼさーへ。いつもそばで見守ってくれてありがとう。
To my Robosa fans. Thank you for always watching over me.
今日で7歳になったんだけど、
I turned 7 today, and...
たぶん、今日の配信のどこかでちょっとポンしたところがあったんだけど、
there was probably a "pon" moment somewhere in today's stream,
気づいちゃった人いるかなー？
but I wonder if anyone noticed?
まぁ、それは後日談でどこかで話したいなって思うんだけど、
Well, I'd like to talk about that as a side story somewhere later, but...
これから、たぶん、まだまだポンなことも、しちゃうと思うけど、
I think I'll probably keep having "pon" moments from now on too, but...
でも、高性能なんでね。
I am high-spec, after all.
もっと高性能なところもいっぱい見せていきたいなって思います。
I want to show you many more high-spec parts of me.
でもポンコツな僕をいつも応援してくれてありがとう。
But thank you for always supporting the clumsy me.
これからも温かい目で見守ってください。
Please continue to watch over me warmly.
たくさん、たくさん、新しい思い出作ろうね。
Let's make many, many new memories together.
大好き。
I love you.
またねー。
See you later.